# Ulises Aroche | Curriculum Vitae

1994 - 28 yo | uapersmail@gmail.com | https://sokratica.github.io/sokratica/cv

#### About Me

MPhil on Philosophy of Science and Bachelor degree in Economics graduated with honors, both studied in the National Autonomous University of Mexico (UNAM). Digging and specializing in security and corporate threat intelligence. I'm currently working on incident attending related to financial, fiscal, credit records, commercial, judicial and communication information, and open source intelligence. I'm starting a new full online-bachelor in Informatics due to my recently discovered interest on the cybersecurity field.

## Experience

[+] Current Intelligence Analyst in Grupo Miura.

I do incident investigations, make reports and present the evidence gathered, relate facts and reconstruct the possible criminal's modus operandi.

Fields, information: financial, fiscal, credit records, commercial, communications, and open source. Period, since September 2021.

- [+] Operational area in UniCCo (Credit Union):
  - Intern since February 2019 to July 2019.
  - Collection executive since March 2021 to July 2021.
- [+] Rural investments projects analyst and technical coordinator in the company *Tendencias*, Consultores en Economía, S.C. Period, since March 2018 to September 2018.

## Languages and Courses

- [+] English intermediate level. Main competency: reading. Reading comprehension certificate by Escuela Nacional de Lenguas, Lingüística y Traducción (ENALLT), UNAM.
- [+] French intermediate level. Main competency: reading. Reading comprehension certificate by Escuela Nacional de Lenguas, Lingüística y Traducción (ENALLT), UNAM.

- [+] Courses
- Python, beginner-intermediate level.
- C.
- Git y Github.
- Google Garage Digital: "Digital Marketing Basic Concepts" (in process).

## **Education**

- [+] MPhil in Philosophy of Science at Unidad de Posgrado / Facultad de Filosofía y Letras, UNAM. Grade point average 9.40. Date of graduation: September 30, 2021.
- [+] Bachelor in Economics, Facultad de Economía, UNAM. Grade point average 9.10 Date of graduation: January 18, 2019.
- [+] Bachelor in Information and Communication Technologies, Instituto Rosario Castellanos. Recently started.

#### General Skills

- [+] Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Visio. Excel intermediate level: Dynamic tables.
- [+] Analysis and reports creation of academic texts and professionals under predefined methodologies.
- [+] Reports creation in text processor LaTex.
- [+] i2 IBM usage to elaborate flow charts.

## Other / Collaborations

- [+] Intern in the research project Mercados financieros contemporáneos. Crisis, deuda exterior y deflación, with PhD Alicia Girón at the Economic Research Institute (IIEc), UNAM, from 2015 to 2016.
- [+] Personal assistant of PhD Monika Meireles in the research project Financiarización, sector bancario y desarrollo: Tendencias y perspectivas. Research project's internal team coordination support, IIEc, UNAM, from 2016 to 2017.
- [+] Intern in the research project Trascendencia del gasto público en la incorporación de las mujeres en el mercado laboral. Trabajo de cuidado y reproducción en América Latina, with PhD

 $María\ Luisa\ González\ Marín\ and\ MD\ Patricia\ Rodríguez\ López\ in\ IIEc,\ UNAM,\ from\ 2018\ to\ 2019.$ 

# Visit my blog

